（日向(ひなた)翔陽(しょうよう)）目の前に立ちはだかる
高い高い壁
A massive, massive wall stands
in front of me, blocking my way.
その向こうはどんな眺めだろうか
I wonder what the view is like on the other side.
What does it look like?
どんなふうに見えるだろうか
俺１人では
決して見ることのできない
It's something I'll never be able to see alone.
The Japanese National High School Boys' Volleyball Tournament Miyagi Prefecture Qualifier
Finals
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
The view from the summit
The view from the summit.
Let's go, Hinata.
（影山(かげやま)飛雄(とびお)）行くぞ日向
（日向）おお
Yeah!
Episode One:
Greetings
Sawamura!
（道宮(みちみや)結(ゆい)）澤村(さわむら)
（澤村(さわむら)大地(だいち)）お
We came to cheer you on!
（道宮）応援に来たよ
Michimiya! You really came.
（澤村）
道宮本当に来てくれたんだ
Wow! You're going to play in the finals!
（道宮）うわホントに
決勝戦うんだねすごいよ
That's amazing! It's so...
もうもうヤバいよ
All right. Let's go, everyone.
Crazy!
Okay.
（女子部員）だからあんたの
ボキャブラリがヤバい
Your lack of vocabulary is what's crazy.
Yui.
（女子部員）結
U-Um...
あああのそれでこれ
So, uh, here!
I mean, it's not just for you.
いやあの別に
個人的にとかじゃなくて—
It's for all of you guys, and for us too, so it's not like—
１個にみんな分ていうか
私たちの分も的なアレであて
別にあの
（澤村）おおありがと
Oh, thanks!
You're so thoughtful, Michimiya.
さすが道宮気が利くな
Huh? I-It's not a big deal...
（道宮）えいいやそんな
I'll put it on the bench.
ベンチに置かせてもらう
じゃ応援よろしく
Hope you'll cheer us on!
You can count on us!
任せて
はあうう
I'm impressed you were even able to give it to him.
あんたにしては
渡せただけ及第点だわ
The Japanese National High School Boys' Volleyball Tournament Miyagi Prefecture Qualifier
Finals
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
Shiratorizawa
vs.
Karasuno
Wow...
（田中(たなか)龍之介(りゅうのすけ)）うわ
So this is the finals.
（田中）さすが決勝人多いな
The place is packed.
（西谷(にしのや)夕(ゆう)）龍(りゅう)
ビビてる場合じゃねえぞ
This is no time to be scared, Ryuu.
I-I'm not scared.
べ別にビビてねえよ
いいか龍想像してみろ
決勝戦相手は白鳥沢(しらとりざわ)
I want you to picture something.
It's the finals.
Our opponents are Shiratorizawa.
What do you think is going to happen when we play to a crowd this big?
これだけの観客の中
活躍したらどうなると思う
What's going to happen?
どうなるて言われても
（女子生徒）やぱうまいと—
They always look so much cooler when they're good players.
それだけで
カコよく見えちゃうよね
はうわ
（田中）うりゃ
（ホイスル）
（田中･西谷）おしゃ
Yeah!
（女子生徒）キャ
西谷君田中君ステキ
Nishinoya! Tanaka! You're amazing!
（西谷･田中）フフフフ
Nishinoya, Tanaka.
（清水(しみず)潔子(きよこ)）西谷君田中君
（２人）あ
Do...
（清水）が頑張て
Do your best out there.
Noya, I'm gonna do this!
ノヤさんやるぜ俺は
I'm gonna become a hero after this match!
この試合で
一躍ヒロになてみせる
I'm not gonna lose, Ryuu!
（西谷）負けねえぞ龍
（２人）うお
They seem more hyped up than usual.
（木下(きのした)久志(ひさし)）
いつもより気合い入てんな
Hey, stop screaming! You're embarrassing us!
Guts! Guts! Guts! Guts!
（縁下(えんのした)力(ちから)）おい
恥ずかしいから叫ぶのやめろ
（西谷･田中）
気合いだ気合いだ
I'm glad those guys never change.
（成田(なりた)一仁(かずひと)）でもいつもどおりで
頼もしいよ
（西谷･田中）
気合いだ気合いだ
（縁下）ふん
Shut up, you two!
（澤村）うるさいお前ら
（縁下）だな
Indeed.
Come on, let's go.
（澤村）ほらささと行くぞ
Right!
（烏野(からすの)部員たち）うす
Hinata, do you need to go to the bathroom?
（田中）日向便所いいのか
ぐわさき行きましたよ
I just went!
Shou!
（泉(いずみ)行高(ゆきたか)）翔(しょう)ちゃん
（日向）お
えイイズミンコジ
I-Izumin! Kouji!
Hey, it's been a while!
（関向(せきむかい)幸治(こうじ)）おす久しぶり
ああおお
（田中）ん
（日向）ああ中学の—
Oh, they're from my junior high volleyball... I mean...
バレ部じゃないけど—
They're the people who helped me during my volleyball match!
試合に出る時に
助けてくれた友達です
（泉）当時バスケ部でした
I was on the basketball team.
I was on the soccer team.
サカ部でした
I was wondering why there was
someone with really good footwork!
どうりで足技うまいヤツいるなと
思たわ
アハハいい
（日向）ん
What the...
（関向）
アイツ何でアイツがいる
Why's he here?!
I said the same thing at first.
俺も最初に同じこと言た
He had a lot going on before.
アイツにも
いろいろ事情がありましてね
Isn't that the King?
王様だろアイツ
大丈夫なのか翔陽
Are you sure you'll be okay, Shouyou?
フヒヒまあ見てろよ
Just watch.
（関向･泉）うん
Hey, let's go, Hinata.
（影山）おい行くぞ日向
あじゃあ応援よろしく
Well, I hope you cheer us on.
Do your best!
頑張れよ
（日向）おうよ
You bet!
We texted, but only about what I was up to.
メルじゃ
こちの話ばかだたからな
Who knew they'd have a reunion?
まさかの再会
Who are they?
誰だアイツら
（泉）翔ちゃん
仲間ができたんだね
They were in the match with me in junior high.
So Shou finally made some friends.
中学で試合しただろ
Shut up. Like I remember everyone I played against.
（泉）翔ちゃん
仲間ができたんだね
うるせえいちいち全員なんか
覚えてねえよ
Yeah.
（関向）ああ
うるせえいちいち全員なんか
覚えてねえよ
（日向）
ああ影山君そんなんだから
友達ができないんだぞ
And that's exactly why you don't have friends, Kageyama.
クてんめえ
What did you say?!
Hey! Stop it, you two!
（澤村）
コラやめろお前ら
You're wasting energy before the finals?
（月島(つきしま)蛍(けい)）これから
決勝戦うていうのに—
Are you guys completely stupid?
よけいな体力使て
バカじゃないの
（山口(やまぐち)忠(ただし)）アハハ
Well, we might immediately lose anyway.
（月島）ますぐに負けるかも
しれないけどね
フフ
（澤村）またくほら行くぞ
Good grief.
Come on, let's get moving.
（澤村）よし上に荷物置いたら
すぐにアプ
As soon as we put our stuff away, we're going to warm up...
Ow! What the heck, Daic—
（菅原(すがわら)孝支(こうし)）アタ何だよ大地
Until recently, they couldn't
even get past the second round.
（横山(よこやま)静康(しずやす)）ついこないだまで
２回戦負けしてたりして—
Karasuno couldn't fly or crow.
鳴かず飛ばずだたからな烏野
Hopefully them making it to finals isn't some fluke, either.
この決勝進出も
まぐれじゃなきゃいいけどな
Oh, that guy's here again?
（鳥養(うかい)繋心(けいしん)）何だあのオサン
また来てたのか
え知り合いですか
Do you know him?
Nah. He would just show up to matches every so often.
いや昔からたまに来ててな
I don't think he's someone's relative, so I think he might
just be a high school volleyball fan that likes Karasuno.
父兄とかではなさそうだから—
単に高校バレファンの
烏野びいきなんじゃねえかな
He'll cheer for plays he thinks
were good and boo the bad ones.
Where's Karasuno's cheering section?
He's always been easy to read.
昔から分かりやすいオサンだよ
You should at least make that clear.
Have you guys seen him before?
お前らも見たことあんのか
Yes.
はいうちらがまだ１年生だた頃
大会に来てまして
When we were first-years, he came to one of our matches.
We'll never let him call us "clipped crows" again.
二度と“地に落ちた”なんて
言わせねえ
Japanese National High School Volleyball Tournament
（日向）ん
All right, here we go!
よし行くぞ
Yeah!
（部員たち）おしゃ
Karasuno's Victory is Certain
They finally made it here.
（滝ノ上(たきのうえ)祐輔(ゆうすけ)）
ついにここまで来たか
Massive
Sale
Yeah.
（嶋田(しまだ)誠(まこと)）
ああ俺たちも本気出すぜ
Let's give it our all too!
Yeah!
（滝ノ上）おお
All right!
（滝ノ上）よしゃ
Ladies and gentlemen from the Karasuno shopping district, Karasuno Alumni Cheer Squad, and cheer squad hopefuls!
集めに集めた烏野商店街
アンドＯＢ応援団
アンド応援志望生徒総勢多数
Let's start by beating Shiratorizawa at cheering!
まずは応援から白鳥沢に勝つ
Fly
Listen up, everyone!
Two, three, four!
（教頭）いいかね諸君
We need to cheer as loud as we can so that our cheers become the players' strength!
（教頭）
我々の応援が選手たちの力になる
Five, six, seven, eight!
を出すように
Right.
（生徒たち）はい
The vice principal sure seems
worked up about this all of a sudden.
（男子生徒）
教頭ここぞとばかりに—
Come on. We need to practice once.
すげえ張り切てんな
Ready, and...
Was he always like that?
（男子生徒）あんなキャラだけ
（教頭）せの
Go, go, Karasuno! Push it, push it, Karasuno!
いけいけ烏野
押せ押せ烏野
（生徒たち）いけいけ烏野
Go, go, Karasuno! Push it, push it, Karasuno!
Hey! We just practiced this yesterday!
（教頭）こりゃ
昨日練習したじゃないか
うん
（教師）教頭先生
Sir, you say we practiced,
but it was just a little bit after school.
練習したて昨日放課後に
ちょこと練習しただけなんで
A-Are they going to be okay?
だ大丈夫かこれ
We can't panic!
（嶋田）
俺たちがうろたえてどうする
Look at them!
アイツらを見ろよ
堂々としたもんじゃねえか
See how confident they are?
（日向）もかい便所
I'm going to the bathroom again!
I-I need an antacid.
（山口）い胃薬を
Me too...
（東峰(あずまね)旭(あさひ)）俺も腹が
We're playing center court...
センタコト
Noya, cheerleaders! They have cheerleaders!
（田中）
ノヤさんチアだチアだぞ
Are you okay, Yamaguchi?!
（西谷）うらやましい
I'm so jealous!
Tanaka, Nishinoya! Will you two shut up already?!
（澤村）田中西谷騒ぐな
You guys are panicking way too hard.
（月島）うろたえすぎでしょ
E-Every... Everyone, calm...
（武田(たけだ)一鉄(いてつ)）落ち落ちつ
みんな落ちちゅ
This is Karasuno?
これが烏野
I'm not anyone suspicious!
（男性）
怪しい者じゃないですてば
I saw this suspicious guy wandering around.
（田中(たなか)冴子(さえこ)）
不審なヤツがうろうろしてて—
He ran when he saw me, so I caught him!
見てたら逃げたから捕まえた
Hey! Stop!
（男性）ちょと
（冴子）白鳥沢のスパイかと思て
I thought he might be a Shiratorizawa spy!
What?!
何
（男性）うう
W-Wait! I'm a relative!
ま待て関係者です
I'm Tsukishima Kei's older brother!
（月島(つきしま)明光(あきてる)）月島蛍の兄です
Tsukishima's older brother?!
（滝ノ上･嶋田）月島の兄貴
（明光）シシ
Shh! Shh!
He told me not to come to the match.
試合には来るなて
言われてるんですよ
（月島）うう
Those two are nothing alike.
こちは似てねえな主に雰囲気が
Especially their personalities.
Huh?
Shiratorizawa!
（白鳥沢応援団）白鳥沢
白鳥沢
All right, here we go!
（応援団員）さあいきましょう
（応援団）さあいきましょう
Be Courageous Warriors
（応援団員）さあいきましょう
（応援団）さあいきましょう
（応援団員）今日の相手は
（応援団）今日の相手は
Our opponent today...
...is Karasuno High School!
（応援団員）烏野高校
（応援団）烏野高校
（烏野応援団の
（応援団員）よろしくよろしく
（応援団）よろしくよろしく
Nice to meet you!
（応援団員）さあいきましょう
（応援団）さあいきましょう
All right, here we go!
Be Courageous Warriors
と手拍子）
All right, here we go!
Wow...
すげえな
（東峰）
ああさすが強豪校て感じだわ
Yeah, they definitely feel like a powerhouse school.
Come to think of it, Shiratorizawa hasn't shown up yet.
そういえば向こうのチム
まだ来ませんね
Yeah, they're late.
（澤村）ああ遅いな
Damn. They must be taking their sweet time.
（田中）クソ何か余裕すね
（東峰）王者の貫録てやつか
Maybe it's their dignity as champions or something.
俺たちのことナメてんすかね
（日向）あ
Are they underestimating us?
来た
They're here!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
All right, let's start our meeting.
（繋心）おし
ミティング始めるぞ
Shiratorizawa Academy
Countermeasure Documents
（一同のため息）
おい今日２試合やて
疲れてんのは分かるが—
Hey, I know you're tired from already playing two matches today, but you'd better listen.
ちゃんと聞いとけよ
明日試合なんだからな
Our next match is tomorrow.
First, I'm going to start with my honest opinion.
まずは俺の率直な感想だが
If the most complete team in the prefecture is Aoba Jousai,
県内で最も完成されたチムが
青葉城西(あおばじょうさい)とするなら—
then Shiratorizawa is the most
incomplete team in the prefecture.
白鳥沢は県内で最も
未完成なチムだ
（菅原･東峰）ん
（澤村）え未完成
Incomplete?
何でそう思うか分かるか
Do you know why I think that?
Because I looked at the file your managers made after
they found out everything they could about Shiratorizawa.
それはお前らのために一生懸命
白鳥沢を調べて作てくれた—
マネジャたちの
この資料を見たからだ
（一同）おお
（西谷･田中）おお
潔子さんが俺のために
Kiyoko did that for me?!
（清水）いやみんなのためです
No, it was for the whole team.
（西谷･田中）ああ
That's really all we can do, anyway.
私たちができることは
これくらいだから
Right, Hitoka?
ね仁花(ひとか)ちゃん
（谷地(やち)仁花(ひとか)）あはい
Oh, yes.
（日向）うお
（谷地）皆さんのお役に立ちたくて
We wanted to be of some use to you all.
Thank you, Yachi!
ありがとう谷地さん
You guys had better not let it go to waste!
お前らムダにすんじゃねえぞ
耳の穴かぽじてよく聞けよ
Clean out those ears and listen!
（部員たち）はい
Yes, sir!
Um, so what do you mean by "incomplete team"?
あの“未完成なチム”て
どういう
俺たちや他の多くのチムが—
If you'd call the attacks we and
most other teams do multiplication,
やろうとしている攻撃が
掛け算なら—
白鳥沢は足し算
個々の強い力の足し算だ
then Shiratorizawa does addition.
They add their strengths together.
速さで位置差で時間差で—
We use different speeds, locations,
and timings for our attacks to get through blocks.
俺たちはブロクをかいくぐる
工夫をする
白鳥沢も時間差を使うが
レシブが多少乱れたり—
Shiratorizawa also varies the timing of their attacks,
but when the receive is a bit off,
or in cases where they really want to score,
確実に点を取りたい場面では
ほぼウイングスパイカ
they set to their wing spikers without fail.
Ushijima especially gets a lot of high sets.
特に牛島(うしじま)に高いトスを集める
理由は１つそれで点が取れるから
There's only one reason for that.
They're sure to score.
（泉）うお
（関向）あああ
Sorry!
（白鳥沢部員）すいません
They'll come out swinging without
thinking twice about our guard.
（繋心）こちのガドなんか
お構いなしにぶん殴られる
And it'll be with power like we've never experienced before.
今まで経験したことのない力でな
You'd better be prepared!
覚悟しとけ
ワンバンでこんなに離れた
２階席まで
He managed to hit that all the way up here?
He hits from so high up!
打点高
They simply destroy everything with their one ultimate spear.
（繋心）１本の最強の矛で
ただ単純にぶ壊す
That's the kind of team Shiratorizawa is.
そういうチムが白鳥沢だ
Though Ushiwaka is their best player,
it's not like the rest of the team is ordinary either.
まウシワカが
最強だつても—
周りのヤツらが
凡庸なはずもないけどな
（天童(てんどう)覚(さとり)）ふあい
Got it!
It feels like they're hitting it so lightly,
yet it looks like it could tear your arms off.
ゆたり打てる感じなのに
触たら腕もげそう
Light it up, Wakatoshi!
（日向）ウシワカやぱすげえな
Ushiwaka's amazing.
Light it up, Wakatoshi!
（影山）ん
I'm excited!
ワクワクすんな
Yeah.
Light it up, Eita!
（ホイスル）
（田中･西谷）よしゃ
Yeah!
（山口）ああ
あざすうお
Thanks!
Light it up, Satori!
（日向）弁慶(べんけい)だ
He's Benkei.
（日向）どうも
That guy's totally Benkei.
（日向）あの人絶対弁慶だ
Leon.
はいよ
What's up?
Leon?!
（日向）レオン
That little kid totally just gave Leon the nickname "Benkei".
（天童）今のちびこ—
君に
“弁慶”てあだ名つけたよね
Sorry to shatter your dreams.
（大平）イメジ違いでごめんな
So that's one of the guys from
Karasuno's first-year fast attack combo.
（瀬見(せみ)英太(えいた)）あれが烏野の
１年速攻コンビの１人か
Oh, it was?!
えそうなの
さあ来い
Bring it!
（女子生徒）見て
Look! There's a tiny kid!
あんなちちゃい子がいる
補欠かな
I wonder if he's a sub.
Nice spike!
（女子生徒）
何かかわいそうになるね
I sort of feel bad for him.
I always feel like cheering for the underdog.
（女子生徒）どうしても弱いほう
応援したくなちゃうよね
Nice spike!
（日向･田中）ナイスキ
Hey, you two.
おいお前ら
昨日のアレやたれ
Do that thing you did yesterday!
（影山･日向）お
But I can say the following with confidence.
でもなこれだけは
自信を持て言える
We definitely won't lose when it comes to scoring points!
点を取る力では絶対に負けてない
First...
まずは
conquer this fight.
殴り合いを制せ
（女子生徒たち）うう
（横山）む
（関向･泉）うわ
あのチビ真下に打ちやがた
（天童）ほ
That shorty hit it straight down!
More importantly, it was so fast!
つか速
今セタ触た
Did the setter even touch it?
I was surprised that Seijou didn't make it this time,
（山形(やまがた)隼人(はやと)）今回青城(せいじょう)が来なくて
驚いたけど—
but Karasuno's pretty interesting too.
おもしろいじゃん烏野
Yeah.
そうだな
It doesn't matter who we're up against. We'll shut them down!
（五色）誰が来たて
力でねじ伏せればいいだけです
Talk big when you can actually back it up.
（白布(しらぶ)賢二郎(けんじろう)）大口はもと
実力つけてからたたけよ
Now, now...
Your bangs and your words are as cool as ever, Tsutomu.
相変わらず言うことと前髪が
カコいいね工は
Thanks!
ありがとうございます
I think you babying him is exactly the problem.
（川西(かわにし)太一(たいち)）そうやて甘やかすの
よくないと思いますよ
You're so harsh, Taichi!
固太一固いよ
I'm just counting on him.
期待してんだよ何たて—
I mean, he's a first-year and a starter and the one who's going to become the ace.
１年でうちのレギュラで
エスになる男なんだから
（五色）ん
I'll do my best to not let you down!
（五色）期待に応えます
（五色）うおおおお
Right. Do your best, future ace.
そうね頑張れ未来のエス
You're just inflating his ego with that talk.
つけあがるから
やめてください
Let's start with receives.
（牛島(うしじま)若利(わかとし)）先レシブだ
We're counting on you yet again, Wakatoshi.
若利君今日も頼むよ
You need to work harder.
お前が頑張んなさいよ
若利にだけ頼るんじゃない
Don't just rely on Wakatoshi.
What are you, his right arm? Are you Benkei?
右腕かよ弁慶かよ
Ushijima!
（五色）牛島さん
（天童）ん
この決勝で—
I'll prove that I'm the one who should
be called the ace in these finals.
俺のほうがエスと呼ばれるに
ふさわしいと—
証明してみせます
Yeah. Do your best.
ああ頑張れ
（五色）うう
（天童）ブホ
He actually said that seriously,
so he comes off as a bit of a jerk.
本心から“頑張れ”て
言ちゃてるから—
ホントタチ悪い
（ホイスル）
Their starting lineup is just as we expected.
（繋心）向こうのスタティングは
予想どおりだ特徴覚えてか
Did you memorize their profiles?
（部員たち）はい
Yes, sir!
We're not going to let Ushijima decide how this goes!
牛島に決められんのは
もう割り切れ
If they score, switch gears and score back!
切り替えて取り返すそれでいい
That's all you need to do!
They aren't machines.
向こうだて機械じゃねえんだ
ミスは必ず出る
They'll mess up sometimes.
やること分かてんな
You know what you need to do, right?
Yes, sir!
（一同）はい
All right, everyone.
さあ皆さん決勝戦です
This is the finals.
Since we got this far, let's win and go to nationals!
ここまで来たからには
勝て全国に行きましょう
Yeah!
（烏野部員たち）おお
Japanese National High School Volleyball Tournament
（ホイスル）
（観客たちの拍手）
（アナウンス）
これより全日本バレボル—
We will now begin the Japanese National
High School Volleyball Tournament,
高等学校選手権大会
宮城県代表決定戦
Miyagi Prefecture Qualifiers, Boys' Finals.
男子優勝決定戦
宮城県立烏野高等学校対—
The match will be Miyagi Prefectural Karasuno High School
versus Shiratorizawa Academy.
白鳥沢学園高等学校の
試合を開始いたします
It's finally starting.
（日向）いよいよだ
ああ翔ちゃん
ホントにこんな舞台に立てるよ
Oh man, Shou really made it to the finals.
Yeah, but are the guys on the other
team actually in high school?!
つか相手
ホントに高校生かよ
がつりテレビとか来(く)んだね
Wow, there are tons of TV crews here.
We will now introduce the
Karasuno High School starting lineup.
（アナウンス）烏野高等学校の—
スタティングプレヤを
紹介いたします
Number one, Sawamura Daichi.
１番澤村大地
３番東峰旭
Number three, Azumane Asahi.
５番田中龍之介
Number five, Tanaka Ryuunosuke.
（冴子）龍
（田中）よしゃ
Ryuu!
Yeah!
Number nine, Kageyama Tobio.
（アナウンス）９番影山飛雄
Number ten, Hinata Shouyou.
10番日向翔陽
11番月島蛍
Number eleven, Tsukishima Kei.
Kei!
（冴子）蛍
（明光）ちょちょとやめて
Hey, stop!
Number four, Libero, Nishinoya Yuu.
（アナウンス）
４番リベロ西谷夕
やほい
Yeah!
（アナウンス）監督武田一鉄
Coach, Takeda Ittetsu.
Next, we will introduce the
Shiratorizawa Academy starting lineup.
（アナウンス）続きまして
白鳥沢学園高等学校の—
スタティングプレヤを
紹介いたします
Number one, Ushijima Wakatoshi.
１番牛島若利
Ushijima!
（女子生徒）牛島君
Waka!
Number four, Oohira Leon.
５番天童覚
Number five, Tendou Satori.
Yay!
イエイ
（アナウンス）８番五色工
Number eight, Goshiki Tsutomu.
（五色）ふん
Number ten, Shirabu Kenjirou.
（アナウンス）10番白布賢二郎
Number twelve, Kawanishi Taichi.
12番川西太一
Number fourteen, Libero, Yamagata Hayato.
14番リベロ山形隼人
しゃあ
Yeah!
Coach, Washijou Tanji.
（アナウンス）監督鷲匠(わしじょう)鍛冶(たんじ)
観客の皆様
両チムの健闘を祈て—
Ladies and gentlemen, please cheer
on both teams and wish them good luck.
援を
お願いいたします
（冴子）ん
アイツらの緊張移てきた
I'm totally starting to feel their nerves.
I thought they were doing okay when I saw
the one spike Hinata made after their warmup.
アプの時の
日向の一発見た時は—
わりといい雰囲気かと
思たけどな
This is a path Shiratorizawa has gone down many times.
向こうにとては何度も踏んだ道
On the other hand, Karasuno is in the finals
and playing center court for the first time.
対してこちは初めての決勝
初めてのセンタコト
You can't blame them for being nervous.
平常でいられないのも
無理ねえよな
決勝が初てことは
５セトマチも初ですか
If this is their first time in the finals,
have they never played a best-of-five before?
Best-of-five?
５セト
今までは２セト先取の
３セトマチだたけど—
Up until now, they played best-of-threes
and the first to two sets won.
In the finals, they play a best-of-five
and the first to three sets wins,
決勝は３セト先取
５セトマチ
just like the pro matches you see on TV.
テレビとかで見る
トプレベルと同じな
What?! That's gonna be super tiring!
えめちゃ疲れるじゃん
Yeah.
それなスタミナも心配だ
I'm worried about their stamina.
あたしらが暗くなてどうする
（谷地）は
We can't be the ones who are gloomy!
This is a different start than usual.
いつもと違うスタトだな
They usually have someone with a good serve
go first or put Hinata in the front row.
いつもはサブ強いヤツか
日向前衛スタトだもんな
I guess they're going to try to match up their tallest blockers against Ushijima.
牛島に対して
できるだけこちの高い壁が—
マチアプするように
じゃねえか
They'll have to see how Shiratorizawa
handles their spikes too.
スパイクをどう対処していくかも
注目だな
Shiratorizawa                 Karasuno
Bring it!
（五色）さあ来い
青葉城西に負け
県内の決勝にも残れない者が—
But someone on a team that can't even make it
to the prefecture finals because they lost to Aoba Jousai
can say all they want, but I will make nothing of it.
何を言てもどうとも思えん
Give us a good serve, Daichi!
（田中）大地さんナイサ
（ホイスル）
Got it!
オライ
（白布）牛島さん
Ushijima!
Here it comes!
（影山･月島･東峰）来た
（牛島）ふん
I got it.
（西谷）とらえた
（ホイスル）
Be Courageous Warriors
Nice spike, Ushijima!
（応援団員）ナイスキ牛島
Ushijima! Ushijima!
（応援団）牛島牛島
Shake it off!
ドンマイ
Get the next one!
次次
Shiratorizawa                  Karasuno
ヒヒ出たな左
Hello there, Left.
（冴子）でその変装はどうなの
So, what's up with your disguise?
A hat and huge sunglasses are like the classic disguise!
（明光）キャプに
デカいグラサンは—
変装の王道じゃないですか
That reminds me, Kageyama wore a similar disguise once.
（谷地）そういえば影山君も—
以前同じような変装してました
（明光）ほらね
See?
That just means you're both equally simpleminded.
（冴子）同レベルにシンプルな
オツムてだけじゃん
Episode Two:
The Threat of "Left"
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回「ハイキュ」
"The Threat of 'Left'."